Juliana Pliger

São Paulo – Brazil ↑ (+55) 41 99739-3176 ↓ Jupliger7@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/juliana-pliger in

Front-End Developer | 4 years of experience

With over 4 years of experience in Front-End development using JavaScript, TypeScript, React.Js, Next.Js, and Angular. I am seeking a position as a Mid-Level Front-End Developer. My main achievements include conducting a POC (Proof of Concept) that led to the global adoption of a data tracking redesign, collaborating with LATAM and USA teams at Bayer for the successful delivery of the first version of the platform, thus creating immersive and responsive web experiences with microservices integration using AWS and Adobe Cloud Manager (EAM). Additionally, I have taught over a thousand hours of programming classes, using technologies such as JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, React Native, Python, and Node.Js.

Skills

JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.Js, React, React Native, Redux, Rest, Angular, Node.Js, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, MySQL, Postman, Firebase, Scrum, Kanban, Azure, Aha!, Monday, Asana, Trello, Storybook, Adobe Cloud, AWS, GIT, WSL, Analytics, Figma, UX/UI, Cyber Security Fundamentals, Discovery, POC.

ACHIEVEMENTS

• POC Analytics - Global Adoption

Refactoring with over 10,000 lines of code in analytics, the new concept was adopted by more than 5 countries.

- Brazil Innovation Sprint Awards The Analyzer
 - Received an award for significant collaboration on the Agro Bayer project.
- Thousand Hours of Programming
 - Over a thousand hours teaching classes using JavaScript, React / React Native, HTML, CSS, and NodeJs.
- Successful Delivery
 - Delivery of a global platform in Agro with LATAM and USA teams.

Experience

Bayer - Front-End Developer

Feb 2023 – Present - São Paulo, Brazil · Hybrid

- Responsible for a refactoring project with over 10,000 lines of code in analytics, the new concept was adopted by more than 5 countries.
- Brazil Innovation Sprint Awards The Analyzer (Analytics / Metrics) Most involved data contributor.
- Integration of components with Adobe AEM and AWS.
- Database integration and API consumption.
- Ensuring a continuous and responsive user interface.
- Implementation of unit tests with Jest.
- Writing documentation and improving overall code quality.
- Presenting new features to global teams in demo meetings.
- Discussing with the technical team about requirements, performance, design, and emerging technologies.
- Collaborating with business areas to align technical requirements with the company's strategic goals.

Tags: JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Redux, Rest, Next, Angular, Node.js, Storybook, Agile, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Git, unit tests, Figma, Adobe AEM, APIs, CI/CD, Jest, technical documentation

Byju's Future School - Programming Teacher

Feb 2021 – Jan 2023 - São Paulo, Brazil · Remote

- Taught children and teenagers to become future developers from scratch.
- Focus on developing games, applications, and web pages.
- The course curriculum included fundamentals and programming logic to machine learning processes.
- Platforms: MIT and CODE.
- Development IDE: ROBLOX STUDIO and VSCODE.

Tags: JavaScript, React.js, React Native, Python, Node.js, HTML, CSS, Git, Figma, APIs, technical documentation, machine learning

Microsoft - Personal Assistant to CEO

Jan 2015 – Jan 2016 - Curitiba, Brazil · On-site

- Documenting decisions on requirements, performance, design, and emerging technologies.
- Sprint maintenance through management platforms (Monday, Trello, Asana).
- Organizing and responding to emails on behalf of the CEO.
- · Creating and organizing documents.
- Reception of stakeholders.
- General assistance.

Education

- Centro Universitário FMU | FIAM-FAAM
 - Bachelor's in Computer Science.
- Kenzie Academy
 - Front-End Development
- Universidade Positivo
 - Game and Application Development

Strengths

- English (C2 advanced);
- Time management;
- Public speaking and impactful presentations.
- Teamwork, pair programming, and war room.
- Influence, resilience, and conflict management.
- Creativity, innovation, and cognitive flexibility.
- Leadership, emotional intelligence, and maker culture.
- Business vision and project management.
- Digital mindset.